<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Octopress | therealmarv]]></title>
  <link href="https://therealmarv.com/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://therealmarv.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-06-10T12:15:00+02:00</updated>
  <id>https://therealmarv.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Marvin Reimer]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switched to Octopress From Blogger]]></title>
    <link href="https://therealmarv.com/switched-to-octopress-from-blogger/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-15T22:03:18+02:00</updated>
    <id>https://therealmarv.com/switched-to-octopress-from-blogger</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I finally switched from Blogger to Octopress. Main reason was that Blogger
itself is not very developer friendly especially if you want to write code like
<code>this is is code</code> in blog posts.</p>

<p><a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> has a wonderful documentation how to get it
running on github pages and the standard design is very good for my needs.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I managed to migrate my old (two only) blog posts from Blogger and get
everything setup on the weekend. I will maybe describe in a seperate posts how
to install, migrate, publish on Github and fine tune Octopress.</p>

<p>Octopress 2.0 also seems a little bit dated and has some small bugs / missing
features and I can strongly recommend the article
<a href="http://blog.alexrothberg.com/2014/05/14/octopress-paper-cuts/">Octopress Paper Cuts</a>
from Alex Rothberg.</p>

<p>The only main thing I do not like on Octopress is that everything is Ruby/Jekyll
based with lots of dependencies (I wonder how smooth upgrading Octopress will
work out) and I wished something like <a href="http://hugo.spf13.com/">Hugo</a> (written in
go and one single binary) would have a bigger fan base. But Octopress beside
Jekyll is the <a href="http://www.staticgen.com/">biggest player on static blog creation systems</a>
and has the most 3rd party plugins. A big dev community is priceless!</p>

<p>I also switch to my own domain entirely and the Github server which is serving
this site has enough bandwidth if I will ever write some meaningful articles
which will get linked to HN ;) :p</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
